Matthew Ranford Full-Stack Software Developer

CONTACT DETAILS

020-4099-4076

matt.ranford16@gmail.com
linkedin.com/in/matthew-ranford-23b759261/
github.com/matthew-ranford
matthew-ranford.github.io/portfolio/

ABOUT

Hi there! I am a full-stack software developer who recently completed Dev Academy Aotearoa and have experience as a painter, landscaper, senior Immigration officer, and various other roles that I am bringing with me into my new career in tech.

I discovered my passion for coding when I started to self-teach myself after work at the beginning of 2023 and when I realized I could take a blank web page from nothing and create something with it I was excited.

My past experiences taught me that I have great discipline, communication skills, teamwork, and an ability to learn new things with a growth mindset. These skills have helped me in the tech space as it is such a collaborative environment and I'm excited by the possibilities to create experiences, provide accessibility, and connect people.

When not coding, I enjoy sports, exercise, mindfulness, reading, Marvel movies/series, travel, quality time with friends, and being in my greenhouse.

EXPERIENCE

Dev Academy Aotearoa, Wellington, NZ | August 2023 - December 2023

Student – Full-stack Software Development Bootcamp

- 17-week intensive software development boot camp of around 800hrs, 60hrs per week that closely represented working in a real-life development team.
- During this time, I learned about using the command line, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript,
 React, Knex, SQLite3, Node, Express, Handlebars, TDD, Restful APIs, Authentication,
 Typescript & GitHub.
- A big focus was on human skills which was a key element to the course where I learned more about myself and enhanced my abilities in communication, courageous conversations, understanding my limitations, giving/receiving feedback, collaboration, empathy, and well-being.
- Each day we completed challenges by pair programming and each week we would complete projects in a group of at least four. This showed me how valuable the human-skills content was when collaborating in these groups using Agile methodologies.

Attention to Detail Decorators, Wellington, NZ | September 2021 – August 2023 Painter/Decorator

Finishing Touch Landscapes, Invermere, BC, Canada | April 2020 – August 2021 Landscape Maintenance

Kicking Horse Coffee, Invermere, BC, Canada | November 2020 – June 2021 Packaging

University Of Lethbridge, Lethbridge, AB, Canada | November 2019 – March 2020 Employment Grounds Worker

Scenic Landscaping, Lethbridge, AB, Canada | May 2019 - October 2019 Landscape Laborer

Panorama Mountain Resort, Invermere, BC, Canada | November 2018 – April 2019

Dishwasher

Colour Up Decorators Ltd, Wellington, NZ | *January 2018 – November 2018*Painter/Decorator

Ministry Of Business, Innovation & Employment, Wellington, NZ | July 2012 – November 2017
Senior Immigration Officer, Immigration Officer, Admin Support Officer/Team Lead

While working in these roles I've acquired the following:

- Growth mindset
- Working independently and learning quickly
- Ability to communicate well with others
- Working well in a team setting
- Dependable
- Discipline
- Trustworthy
- Honesty
- Adaptable
- Eye for detail
- Great time management
- Enjoys learning and trying new things

EDUCATION

Dev Academy Aotearoa, Wellington, NZ | August 2023 - December 2023

New Zealand Certificate in Applied Software Development (Level 6)

REFERENCES

Available on request

^{*}For a comprehensive breakdown of my previous roles, please see LinkedIn*